A Register of the S. V. (Sviatoslav Varlaamovich) Denisov Papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Correspondence, 1917-1957 and undated.
  - Nikon (Rklitskii), Bishop, 1949-1955. (Folder 11: 31)
    Includes materials pertaining to the Diocesan Publishing House in New York
  - Novaia zaria, 1939 (Folder 11: 32)
  - Novoe russkoe slovo, 1930-1957 and undated (Folder 11: 33)
  - Oberoutcheff Publishing Fund, 1929. (Folder 11: 34)
    Includes Ot gruppy pochitatelei pamiati K. M. Oberucheva
  - Obolenskii, Prince, undated (Folder 11: 35)
  - Obshchekazachii zhurnal, 1951 and undated (Folder 11: 36)
  - Obshcherossiiskoe monarkhicheskoe ob"edinenie, 1950-1951 and undated (Folder 11: 37)
  - Obshchestvennoe predstavitel'stvo donskikh i obshchekazach'ikh stanits i khutorov v korolevstve S. Kh. i S., 1928-1930 and undated (Box-folder 12: 1)
  - Obshchestvo gallipoliitsev v Severnoi Amerike, 1951. (Folder 12: 2)
    Includes two issues of Informatsionnyi biuleten' otdela o-va Gallipoliitsev v S.A.S.Sh.
  - Officers of the Russian Imperial Army and Navy, 1923-1952 and undated (Folder 12: 3)
  - Ofitserskoe sobranie, 1921-1922 (Folder 12: 4)
  - Ordeli, Ivan Georgievich, 1937-1939 (Folder 12: 5)
  - Orekhov, Vasilii, 1930-1938 (Folder 12: 6)
  - Padalkin, A., 1952 (Folder 12: 7)
  - Palamar, Timko, undated (Folder 12: 8)
  - Panin, Sergei, 1950 (Folder 12: 9)
  - Pantiukhov, Oleg I., 1930-1939 and undated (Folder 12: 10)
  - Panov, Mikhail, 1939 (Folder 12: 11)
  - Pavlov, Aleksei Petrovich, 1951-1952 (Folder 12: 12)
  - Penner, Sidney L., undated (Folder 12: 13)
  - Persianov, Dmitrii Andreevich, 1948-1953 and undated (Folder 12: 14)
  - Pervushin, G., 1945-1950 and undated (Folder 12: 15)
  - Peterson, Oscar, Senator, 1953 and undated (Folder 12: 16)
  - Petropavlovskii, Vitalii, 1948-1949 (Folder 12: 17)
  - Petrov, Pavel, 1948-1951 (Folder 12: 18)
  - Petrov, V., 1936 (Folder 12: 19)
  - Petrova, Ekaterina Vasil'evna, 1939 (Folder 12: 20)
  - Petrova, Faina Ivanovna, 1952 (Folder 12: 21)
  - Pirash, Andrei, 1924 (Folder 12: 22)
  - Platon (Rozhdestvenskii), Metropolitan, 1924-1926 and undated (Folder 12: 23)
  - Pleshko, Nikolai Dmitrievich, 1925 (Folder 12: 24)
  - Pokhlebin, Sviatoslav Mikhailovich, 1949-1951 (Folder 12: 25)
  - Pokhlebina, Inna, 1951-1953 (Folder 12: 26)
  - Poliakov, Ivan Alekseevich
    - 1922-1949 and undated (Folder 12: 27)
    - 1950 (Folder 12: 28)
    - 1951 (Folder 12: 29)
    - 1952 (Box 13)
      - January – June (Folder 13: 1)
      - July – December (Folder 13: 2)
    - 1953-1956 (Folder 13: 3)
  - Poliakov, Sergei Petrovich, 1928-1955 (Folder 13: 4)
  - Poliakov, V. E., 1928-1951 (Folder 13: 5)
  - Polkovnikov, Sergei Petrovich, 1939-1952 and undated (Folder 13: 6)
  - Polkovnikova, Tatiana, 1945 and undated (Folder 13: 7)
  - Polushkin, N. S., 1928 (Folder 13: 8)
  - Popov, Nikolai Mikhailovich, 1917-1953 (Folder 13: 9)
  - Popov, Petr Kharitonovich, 1934-1950 and undated (Folder 13: 10)
  - Popov, S. V., undated (Box-folder 14: 1)
  - Popov, Timofei Timofeevich, 1950-1951 and undated (Folder 14: 2)
  - Popov, V. K., 1921 (Folder 14: 3)
  - Popov, Viktor Pavlovich, 1945 (Folder 14: 4)
  - Popova, E., 1952 (Folder 14: 5)
  - Posev, 1952 (Folder 14: 6)
  - Postel's, Fedor Fedorovich de, 1946-1954. (Folder 14: 7)
    Includes correspondence relating to Soiuz revnitelei pamiati imperatora Nikolaia II
  - Pozdeev, K., 1951-1956 (Folder 14: 8)
  - Pozdnyshev, Sergei Dmitrievich, 1945-1952 and undated (Folder 14: 9)
  - Pozhydaev, Vsevolod, 1947 (Folder 14: 10)
  - Pravoe dielo, undated (Folder 14: 11)
  - Pravoslavnaia Rus', 1939-1953 and undated (Folder 14: 12)
  - Prigodina, Iuliia L'vovna, 1943-1945 and undated. (Folder 14: 13)
    Includes typed poems by Iu. Prigodina
  - Puchkov, Fedor Abramovich, 1950-1951 and undated (Folder 14: 14)
  - Puchkov, Petr, 1924 (Folder 14: 15)
  - Puchkova, Evlampiia Fedorovna, 1949-1950 (Folder 14: 16)
  - Pushkarev, Sergei Germanovich, 1950-1953 (Folder 14: 17)
  - Rak, A., 1947-1949 (Folder 14: 18)
  - Rakovskii, Grigorii Nikolaevich, 1937-1939 (Folder 14: 19)
  - Reida, Antonii, 1939 (Folder 14: 20)
  - Rein, Nikolai, von, 1951 (Folder 14: 21)
  - Rentskii, Dmitrii Mikhailovich, 1952 (Folder 14: 22)
  - Riasnianskii, Sergei Nikolaevich, 1947-1956 (Folder 14: 23)
  - Rikovskii, V., 1952-1955 (Folder 14: 24)
  - Rodionov, Ivan Aleksandrovich, undated (Folder 14: 25)
  - Rodionov, Vasilii Vasilievich, 1946-1951 and undated (Folder 14: 26)
  - Rodionova, A., 1948 and undated (Folder 14: 27)
  - Rodionova, I., 1947-1948 (Folder 14: 28)
  - Rossiia
    - 1934-1939 and undated (Folder 14: 29)
    - 1940-1953 (Folder 14: 30)
  - Rossiiskii antikommunisticheskii tsentr, 1950-1951 (Box-folder 15: 1)
  - Rossiiskii obshche-voinskii soiuz (ROVS), 1930-1951 (Folder 15: 2)
  - Rossiiskii osvoboditel'nyi soiuz, 1934-1952 (Folder 15: 3)
  - Rossiiskoe tsentral'noe ob"edinenie, 1930 (Folder 15: 4)
  - Rotov, Dmitrii Mikhailovich, 1950 (Folder 15: 5)
  - Rotov, Mikhail, 1952 (Folder 15: 6)
  - Rozenshil'd, Mikhail Vladimirovich, 1938 (Folder 15: 7)
  - Rudichenko, Georgii Petrovich, 1937-1950 and undated (Folder 15: 8)
  - Rusanovich, N., 1954 (Folder 15: 9)
  - Russia-America Transatlantic Corporation, 1925 and undated (Folder 15: 10)
  - Russian American Book Agency "Vek,", 1936 (Folder 15: 11)
  - Russian American Union for Protection and Aid to Russians Outside Russia, 1946-1955 (Folder 15: 12)
  - Russian Charity Society, 1930 (Folder 15: 13)
  - Russian Christian Orthodox Workers in the U.S.A., 1951 (Folder 15: 14)
  - Russian Orthodox Church Outside Russia, 1943-1953 and undated (Folder 15: 15)
  - Russian-American Anti-Communist League, 1931. (Folder 15: 16)
    See also Subject file/Russian émigré anti-communist organizations
  - Russia's Salvation Fund, 1929-1945 (Folder 15: 17)
  - Russkaia gazeta, 1923 and undated (Folder 15: 18)
  - Russkaia mysl', undated (Folder 15: 19)
  - Russkaia zhizn', 1939-1951 and undated (Folder 15: 20)
  - Sabov, Mr., 1951 (Folder 15: 21)
  - Sadovskii, Petr S., 1939 (Folder 15: 22)
  - Sakhno-Ustimovich, Iurii, 1924 (Folder 15: 23)
  - Sammer, N. E., 1949 (Folder 15: 24)
  - Samsonov, Boris, 1950 (Folder 15: 25)
  - Sanin, Nikolai, Reverend, 1944-1949 and undated (Folder 15: 26)
  - Savelov, Leonid Mikhailovich, 1946-1947 and undated. (Folder 15: 27)
    Includes incomplete memoir by N. A. Savelova, "Iz moikh vospominanii"
  - Savitskii, S. V., 1936 (Folder 15: 28)
  - Sechinskii, Iaroslav, 1951 (Folder 15: 29)
  - Semenetskii, Ioann, Reverend, 1952 (Folder 15: 30)
  - Semenov, Aleksei Ivanovich, 1950-1952 (Folder 15: 31)
  - Semenov, Grigorii Mikhailovich, 1937 (Folder 15: 32)
  - Senchenova, Nataliia, 1951 (Folder 15: 33)
  - Serafim (Ivanov), Bishop, 1946-1965. (Folder 15: 34)
    Includes "Obrashchenie gruppy mirian iurisdiktsii vysokopreosviashchenneishago mitropolita Vladimira, ekzarkha sviateishago patriarkha vselenskago," 1951, typescript; and "The Patriarchal Ukaz of February 16, 1945," 1945. Printed copy
  - Serebriankin, Evgenii, 1946 (Folder 15: 35)
  - Sergeev, Anatolii Evgen'evich, undated (Folder 15: 36)
  - Sergievskii, Boris Vasil'evich, 1937-1953 (Folder 15: 37)
  - Shakhovskaia-Nabokova, Nataliia, 1949 (Box-folder 16: 1)
  - Shaliakin, Fedor Gavrilovich, 1949 (Folder 16: 2)
  - Shaposhnikov, Vasilii, Reverend, 1947-1948 (Folder 16: 3)
  - Sharikov, Konstantin, 1950-1951 and undated (Folder 16: 4)
  - Shatilov, Pavel N., 1933-1934 (Folder 16: 5)
  - Shcherbakova, Mariia Mikhailovna, 1939-1948 and undated (Folder 16: 6)
  - Sherstobitov, D., 1952 (Folder 16: 7)
  - Sherstobitov, Mikhail, 1949 (Folder 16: 8)
  - Shibalkin, Pavel N., 1952 (Folder 16: 9)
  - Shirskov, Iakov Vasil'evich, undated (Folder 16: 10)
  - Shmidt, Vladimir Petrovich, 1937-1939 (Folder 16: 11)
  - Shpakovich, A., 1923 and undated (Folder 16: 12)
  - Shul'gin, Aleksandr Nikitovich, 1946 (Folder 16: 13)
  - Shveder, Irina, 1948-1949 (Folder 16: 14)
  - Sidkov, N., 1949 (Folder 16: 15)
  - Sikorsky, Igor Ivanovich, 1937-1949 and undated (Folder 16: 16)
  - Simmov, Mr., 1950 (Folder 16: 17)
  - Sinkevich, Sergei Fedorovich, 1948-1951 (Folder 16: 18)
  - Sitchenkov, Ivan Vladimirovich, 1950-1952 and undated (Folder 16: 19)
  - Sitnikov, M., 1952 (Folder 16: 20)
  - Skey, Mr., 1939 (Folder 16: 21)
  - Skorikov, Ivan Nikolaevich, 1949-1952 (Folder 16: 22)
  - Sladkov, T., 1923-1924 and undated (Folder 16: 23)
  - Slatin, A., 1950 (Folder 16: 24)
  - Society for the Relief of Russian War Invalids Outside of Russia, Inc., 1937-1947 and undated (Folder 16: 25)
  - Soiuz russkikh ofitserov, uchastnikov voiny, 1924, 1950 and undated (Folder 16: 26)
  - Soiuz russkikh veteranov, 1930-1933 and undated (Folder 16: 27)
  - Soiuz vzaimopomoshchi russkikh ofitserov v Danii, 1925 (Folder 16: 28)
  - Soiuz starshin sobraniia ofitserov, uchastnikov velikoi i grazhdanskoi voin, 1930-1931 and undated (Folder 16: 29)
  - Sokolov, Vladimir, 1930 (Folder 16: 30)
  - Solonevich, Ivan Luk'ianovich, 1950 (Folder 16: 31)
  - Solov'ev, Nikolai Nikolaevich, 1937-1952 (Folder 16: 32)
  - Stegov, Petr Evgrafovich, 1951 (Folder 16: 33)
  - Steine, Evgenii Fedorovich, 1939-1951 (Folder 16: 34)
  - Stimson, Henry L., 1929 (Folder 16: 35)
  - Stupenkov, A., 1937 (Folder 16: 36)
  - St. Tikhon's Russian Orphan Home, 1943-1947 and undated (Folder 16: 37)
  - Sviechin, Mikhail Andreevich, 1939-1948 and undated (Folder 16: 38)
  - Sviet, 1937-1939 and undated (Folder 16: 39)
  - Tal'berg, Nikolai Dmitrievich, 1925-1952 (Folder 16: 40)
  - Tabunshchikov, Aleksandr, 1950 (Folder 16: 41)
  - Tatarkina, Vera Dmitrievna, 1951-1952 and undated (Folder 16: 42)
  - Tekuchev, Nikolai Sergeevich, 1947-1949 (Folder 16: 43)
  - Testin, V. N., 1934-1952 and undated (Folder 16: 44)
  - Tikhon (Troitskii), Archbishop, 1952 (Folder 16: 45)
  - Tkachenko, Nikolai Grigor'evich, 1940-1950 (Folder 16: 46)
  - Tolstoy Foundation, 1942-1952 and undated (Folder 16: 47)
  - Tomanovskii, Sergei, 1925 (Folder 16: 48)
  - Trubetskoi, Nikolai Petrovich, 1946 and undated (Folder 16: 49)
  - Trubetskoi, Vladimir Petrovich, 1949-1950 (Box-folder 17: 1)
  - Tschebotarioff, Georgii P., 1938-1947 (Folder 17: 2)
  - Tsentral'noe pravlenie ob"edinennykh russkikh natsional'nykh organizatsii, 1932 (Folder 17: 3)
  - Tsygankov, Mikhail Illarionovich, 1949 (Folder 17: 4)
  - Tulinov, N., 1956 and undated (Folder 17: 5)
  - Turetskii, Loggin Konstantinovich, 1949-1952 and undated (Folder 17: 6)
  - Turkul, Anton Vasil'evich, 1921 (Folder 17: 7)
  - Tyshkevich, Ivan Vasil'evich, 1947 (Folder 17: 8)
  - Ughet, S. A., 1929 (Folder 17: 9)
  - Ukrainian American Relief Committee, 1946 (Folder 17: 10)
  - Ulagai, S., undated (Folder 17: 11)
  - Ushakov, A., 1949 (Folder 17: 12)
  - Uspenskaia, O., 1948-1949 (Folder 17: 13)
  - Ustiuchenkov, Fedor, Reverend, 1951 (Folder 17: 14)
  - Vagin, Aleksandr Nikolaevich, 1938 (Folder 17: 15)
  - Vasil'ev, Pavel, 1917-1951 (Folder 17: 16)
  - Vasil'ev, V., 1938 (Folder 17: 17)
  - Vedeniaev, Mikhail, 1923 (Folder 17: 18)
  - Veimarn, Mikhail Aleksandrovich, 1951-1952 and undated (Folder 17: 19)
  - Veniaminov, A., Reverend, undated (Folder 17: 20)
  - Viernost', undated (Folder 17: 21)
  - Vestnik kazakov zemledel'tsev, undated (Folder 17: 22)
  - Vetrov, P., 1952 (Folder 17: 23)
  - Vinogradov, Vasilii, Reverend, 1931 and undated (Folder 17: 24)
  - Vishnevskii, N. I., 1948-1951 (Folder 17: 25)
  - Vitalii (Maksimenko), Archbishop, 1951-1952 and undated. (Folder 17: 26)
    See also Correspondence/Holy Trinity Monastery
  - Vitalii (Ustinov), Archimandrite (later Archbishop and Metropolitan), 1951 (Folder 17: 27)
  - Vitkovskii, Vladimir Konstantinovich, 1934-1951 and undated (Folder 17: 28)
  - Vladimirskii, Aleksandr, Reverend, 1944-1953 (Folder 17: 29)
  - Vorob'ev, I., Reverend, 1935-1936 and undated (Folder 17: 30)
  - Voskhod, 1936 (Folder 17: 31)
  - Vozrozhdenie, 1939 (Folder 17: 32)
  - Vrangel', Ol'ga Mikhailovna, 1945-1951 and undated (Folder 17: 33)
  - Vyrypaev, Vasilii Osipovich, 1939 (Folder 17: 34)
  - Vysshii monarkhicheskii soviet, 1923-1930 and undated (Folder 17: 35)
  - White, Dmitrii Nikolaevich, 1939 (Folder 17: 36)
  - White, Georgii Ivanovich, 1947 (Folder 17: 37)
  - Zaitsev, Pavel Ivanovich, 1939 and undated (Folder 17: 38)
  - Zakhanevich, Vsevolod Aleksandrovich, 1949-1952 (Folder 17: 39)
  - Zaretskii, Mikhail, 1952 (Folder 17: 40)
  - Zelik, P., 1952 (Folder 17: 41)
  - Zenchik, Ia., 1949 (Folder 17: 42)
  - Zen'kovskii, A. V., 1950 (Folder 17: 43)
  - Zharov, Sergei Alekseevich, 1937-1939 and undated. (Folder 17: 44)
    Includes concert programs
  - Zhelnovach, G., 1938 (Folder 17: 45)
  - Zhiglevich, Leonid Iakovlevich, 1937 and undated (Folder 17: 46)
  - Zimin, N., undated (Folder 17: 47)
  - Zinkevich, Mr., 1939 (Folder 17: 48)
  - Znamenskii, Aleksandr, Reverend, 1947-1949 and undated (Folder 17: 49)
  - Znamenskii, Georgii Aleksandrovich, 1930-1950 and undated (Folder 17: 50)
  - Znamia Rossii, 1939-1953 and undated (Folder 17: 51)
  - Zolotarev, Mikhail M., 1948 (Folder 17: 52)
  - Zotov, Aleksandr Il'ich, 1949-1950 and undated (Folder 17: 53)
  - Zubov, Grigorii Nikolaevich, 1950-1951 (Box-folder 18: 1)
  - Zubov, N., 1951 (Folder 18: 2)
  - Zubov, Petr Petrovich, 1937-1938 (Folder 18: 3)
  - Miscellany, undated (Folder 18: 4)
- Speeches and writings, 1919-1956 and undated.
  Articles, clippings, drafts, monograph, notes, and speeches, arranged chronologically by title
  - General
    - Bibliographies, 1932-1951 and undated (Folder 18: 5)
    - Letters to the editor, 1939-1956 and undated (Folder 18: 6)
    - Notebooks, undated (Folder 18: 7)
    - Notes
      - General, 1929, 1950 and undated (Folder 18: 8)
      - Alexander II, undated (Folder 18: 9)
      - Circulars, undated (Folder 18: 10)
      - Cossack history, undated (Folder 18: 11)
      - Denikin, Anton Ivanovich, General.
        Includes clippings and undated typescripts of articles
      - Don Cossack affairs, 1919 (Folder 18: 12)
      - Don Cossacks in the Russian Civil War, 1939 and undated (Folder 18: 13)
      - Forced repatriation in Lienz, Austria, undated (Folder 18: 14)
      - Russian Civil War, undated (Folder 18: 15)
      - Russkii belyi krest, undated (Folder 18: 16)
      - White Army movement, 1937 and undated (Folder 18: 17)
      - Vasilii Matveevich Rodionov, undated (Folder 18: 18)
        obituary
      - World War II, undated (Folder 18: 19)
  - "Bielyi banket v N'iu Iorkie,", undated. (Folder 18: 20)
    Typescript
  - "Kazak-poet,", undated. (Folder 18: 21)
  - "Ko dniu iubileia general ot kavalerii P. N. Krasnova,", undated. (Folder 18: 22)
    Typescript. Includes handwritten corrections
  - "O mitingakh v pamiat' Generala Kutepova,", undated. (Folder 18: 23)
    Holograph
  - "Pamiati donskogo atamana general-leitenanta Bogaevskogo,", undated. (Folder 18: 24)
    Holograph. Includes typescript notes
  - "Pamiati nezabvennogo druga (Ivana Feodorovicha Mategorina),", undated. (Folder 18: 25)
  - "Po povodu Russko-Finskago mitinga, sostoiavshegosia 21 ianvaria s. g. v gor. N'iu Iorkie,", undated. (Folder 18: 26)
  - "Put' russkogo ofitsera,", undated. (Folder 18: 27)
  - "Svietloi pamiati bielago vozhdia rytsaria, general ot kavalerii donskogo atamana Kaledina,", undated. (Box-folder 19: 1)
  - "Svietloi pamiati generala Iudenicha," incomplete, undated. (Folder 19: 2)
  - "Svietloi pamiati Vsevelikago voiska donskogo, general leitenanta Petra Ivanovicha Grekova,", undated. (Folder 19: 3)
  - "Svietloi pamiati bielago vozhdia generala Drozdovskago i ego boevykh soratnikov,", undated. (Folder 19: 4)
  - Untitled article about General Petr N. Krasnov, undated. (Folder 19: 5)
  - "Zhizn' kazakov v N'iu Iorkie,", undated. (Folder 19: 6)
  - "Organizatsiia kazakov v Turtsii,", 1922. (Folder 19: 7)
  - "Otviet g-nu Aleksieiu Bekhtieevu,", 1924. (Folder 19: 8)
    Printed copy
  - "Diela kazach'i,", 1934. (Folder 19: 9)
    Typescript. Includes related correspondence
  - "Nashi dostizheniia,", 1934. (Folder 19: 10)
  - "Rossiia i eia rol' v velikoi voinie,", 1934. (Folder 19: 11)
  - Bielaia Rossiia: Al'bom #1, 1937
    - General (Folder 19: 12)
    - Background materials (Folder 19: 13-14)
    - Correspondence
      - 1929 and undated (Folder 19: 15)
      - 1937-1938 (Folder 19: 16)
      - 1939 (Box-folder 20: 1)
      - 1940-1956 (Folder 20: 2)
    - Draft, incomplete, undated. (Folder 20: 3)
      Holograph and typescript
    - Financial documents, 1937-1954 and undated (Folder 20: 4)
  - "Ko dniu traditsionnoi kazachei molitvennoi Trizny-13 fevralia 1949 g.," (Folder 20: 5)
    Typescript. Includes undated speech on same topic
  - "Kazachestvo,", 1951. (Folder 20: 6)
- Subject file, 1900-1966 and undated.
  Announcements, appeals, articles, biographical sketch, bylaws, circulars, clippings, correspondence, financial documents, leaflets, lists, lottery tickets, maps, military service records, minutes, notes, obituaries, orders, questionnaire, registration card, reports, resolutions, statutes, pamphlets, schedules and syllabi, arranged alphabetically by subject
  - All-Cossack Union in the United States
    - General (Folder 20: 7)
    - Announcements (Folder 20: 8)
    - Circulars (Box-folder 21: 1)
    - Correspondence (Folder 21: 2-4)
    - Financial documents (Folder 21: 5)
    - Information bulletin (Folder 21: 6)
    - Lists of members, 1928-1949 (Folder 21: 7)
    - Minutes (Box-folder 22: 1)
    - Orders (Folder 22: 2)
    - Reports, resolutions (Folder 22: 3)
    - Statutes (Folder 22: 4)
  - Denikin, Anton Ivanovich, articles and clippings (Folder 22: 5)
  - Don Cossacks
    - Ataman elections in the diaspora
      - Correspondence (Folder 22: 6)
      - Clippings (Folder 22: 7-9)
      - Clippings (Box-folder 23: 1)
      - Leaflets, 1935-1958 and undated (Folder 23: 2)
    - Cossack life in emigration. (Folder 23: 3)
      Clippings, correspondence, and other materials
    - Donskoi atamanskii vestnik, 1952-1953 and undated (Folder 23: 4)
    - Fond pomoshchi Lidii Fedorovnoi Krasnovoi (later – General Krassnoff's Welfare Society)
      - General (Folder 23: 5)
      - Correspondence (Folder 23: 6)
      - Financial documents (Folder 23: 7)
      - Resolutions (Folder 23: 8)
      - Trustee elections (Folder 23: 9)
    - History (Folder 23: 10)
    - Lienz, Austria. (Folder 23: 11)
      Materials on the forced repatriation of Cossacks in 1945
    - Lists
      - Deceased cossacks (Folder 23: 12)
      - Veterans, 1921 (Folder 23: 13)
    - Obshchekazachii sel'skokhoziaistvennyi soiuz, 1921. (Folder 23: 14)
      Includes minutes
    - Obshchestvo revnitelei donskoi istorii i pravdy. Bylaws, 1921 (Box-folder 24: 1)
    - Orders, 1907-1913 (Folder 24: 2)
    - Popov, Petr Kharitonovich, undated. (Folder 24: 3)
      See also Correspondence/Poliakov, Ivan Alekseevich and Correspondence/Popov, Petr Kharitonovich
    - Miscellany (Folder 24: 4)
  - Egarskii, Nikolai, 1900-1923. (Folder 24: 5)
    Personal documents and military service record
  - Fond spaseniia rodiny imeni vel. kn. Nikolaia Nikolaevicha (Folder 24: 6)
  - Georgievskie kavalery. (Folder 24: 7)
    Includes clippings, notes and photographs
  - Grabbe, Georgii, Reverend. (Folder 24: 8)
    Materials relating to the Goleniewski affair
  - Grad Kitezh publishing house, 1921-1923 and undated (Folder 24: 9)
  - Kazachii blagotvoritel'nyi fond, 1944-1951 and undated (Folder 24: 10)
  - Kerensky, Alexander F., 1965-1966. (Folder 24: 11)
    Clippings
  - Khegstrem, Aleksandr Petrovich, undated (Folder 24: 12)
  - Khram-pamiatnik tsaria muchenika Nikolaia II, Brussels, Belgium (Folder 24: 13)
  - Kirienko, Ivan Kas'ianovich, 1917-1938 and undated. (Folder 24: 14)
    Includes biographical data, correspondence, and report about the life of the St. George regiment
  - Kirill Vladimirovich, Grand Duke of Russia (Folder 24: 15)
  - Komitet pomoshchi russkim voennopliennym i razorennym voinoi (Folder 24: 16)
  - Komitet russkoi kolonii v Konstantinopole (Folder 24: 17)
  - Korpus imperatorskoi armii i flota, registration card and questionnaire, 1930 (Folder 24: 18)
  - Kruzhok pomoshchi kazakam velikoi Rossii zagranitsei. (Folder 24: 19)
    Includes correspondence, minutes, and notes
  - Ladies committee for charity of American and Canadian Russian Orthodox diocese, 1951-1952 (Folder 24: 20)
  - Liga vozrozhdeniia kazachestva ( Kazach'e dielo, No. 2, 19??. (Folder 24: 21)
    Printed copy, cover page missing)
  - Mariia Fedorovna, Empress of Russia (Folder 24: 22)
  - Morozov, Vasilii Ivanovich. Obituary, undated (Folder 24: 23)
  - Ob"edinennye russkie ofitserskie obshchestva v Iugoslavii, 1931 and undated. (Folder 24: 24)
    Includes announcements and lottery tickets
  - Radio Liberty, 1955-1957 and undated. (Folder 24: 25)
  - Rossiiskaia kommunisticheskaia partiia, 1922. (Folder 24: 26)
    Circulars and letters of the Avtonomnaia gruppa R.K.P. v Germanii
  - Rossiiskii Obshche-Voinskii Soiuz (ROVS)
    - General (Folder 24: 27)
    - Appeals (Folder 24: 28)
    - Imnadze, Evgenii S., General. Correspondence, incoming and outgoing (Folder 24: 29)
    - Informatsionnyi biulleten' (Box-folder 25: 1)
    - Miller, Evgenii Karlovich, General, undated (Folder 25: 2)
      biographical sketch and clipping
  - Rossiiskoe obshchestvo krasnogo kresta v Iugoslavii, 1929 (Folder 25: 3)
  - Rossiiskoe obshche-monarkhicheskoe sovieshchanie v N'iu-Iorkie (Postoiannoe soveshchanie rossiiskikh monarkhicheskikh deiatelei v zarubezh'e), 1953 and undated. (Folder 25: 4)
  - Russia--History
    - Academicians (Folder 25: 5)
    - Cossacks
      - General (Folder 25: 6)
      - Kuban Cossacks (Folder 25: 7)
    - Revolution, 1917 (Folder 25: 8)
    - Refugees, 1924-1972 and undated. (Folder 25: 9)
  - Russia. Territory under White Armies
    - General, 1917-1919 and undated. (Folder 25: 10)
      Clippings, correspondence, leaflets, and maps
    - Donskaia armiia, 1917-1919 (Folder 25: 11)
  - Russian children's welfare society, 1929-1936 and undated (Folder 25: 12)
  - Russian émigré anti-communist organizations (Folder 25: 13)
  - Russian émigré social and charitable organizations, 1923-1968 and undated (Folder 25: 14)
  - Russian Refugee Relief Society of America, Inc., undated (Folder 25: 15)
  - Russian-American Union for Protection and Aid to Russians Outside of Russia, Inc., 1947-1951 (Folder 25: 16)
  - Russians--Czechoslovakia, 1920 and undated. (Folder 25: 17)
    Notebook with notes and pasted clippings
  - Russians--Far East
    - General (Folder 25: 18)
    - Correspondence (Folder 25: 19)
    - "Pomoshch' Dal'nemu Vostoku,", 1929 and undated. (Folder 25: 20)
      Clippings, holograph
    - Printed matter (Folder 25: 21)
  - Russians--Tubabao, Philippines (Box-folder 26: 1)
  - Russians--United States, 1932-1966 and undated. (Folder 26: 2)
  - Russkaia lietniaia dietskaia shkola, 1935 and undated. (Folder 26: 3)
    Includes course outlines, exams, and notes
  - Russkaia pravoslavnaia tserkov'
    - General. (Folder 26: 4)
      Includes epistles addressed to Don Cossacks
    - Diocese of Western America and San Francisco. (Folder 26: 5)
      Includes materials on Archbishop Ioann (Maksimovich)
  - Russkaia shkola v Konstantinopole (Folder 26: 6)
  - Russkoe dielo, 1943-1946. (Folder 26: 7)
    Printed copies, published by R-Press, New York, N.Y.
  - Shkurkin, Pavel Vasil'evich (Folder 26: 8)
  - Sitnikov, Grigorii Alekseevich, 1921. (Folder 26: 9)
    Includes list of Don Cossacks to be recruited, and incomplete article by General Sitnikov.
  - Soiuz mladorossov, 1931 (Folder 26: 10)
  - Soiuz russkikh invalidov (Folder 26: 11)
  - Soiuz russkikh veteranov vsekh voin (Folder 26: 12)
  - Soiuz spaseniia Rossii (Fond spaseniia Rossii) (Folder 26: 13)
  - St. Nicholas Russian Orthodox Church, Stratford, CT (Folder 26: 14)
  - St. Sergius High School, New York (Folder 26: 15)
  - Ukraine--History, 1939-1959 (Folder 26: 16)